A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Governor's Office, 1946, 1970-1985
Library of Virginia
- Governor Mills E. Godwin, Jr., 1974-1977 (accession 43290)., Extent: 2 folders. (Box 1)
  - EO 37 (1976) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Human Resources (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 38 (1976) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Public Safety (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 39 (1976) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Transportation (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 40 (1976) Assignment of the Functions of the Virginia Community Coordinated Child Care (4-C) Advisory Council to the Commission for Children and Youth (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 41 (1976) Office of Special Programs (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 42 (1976) State Office of Volunteerism (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 43 (1976) Issue Identification and Analysis (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 44 (1976) Department of Planning and Budget (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 45 (1976) Governor's Manpower Services Council (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 46 (1976) Governor's Manpower Planning Council (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 47 (1976) Virginia's Historic Landmarks (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arbor Day (12 March 1976), signed 9 March 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Peter Francisco Day (15 March 1976), signed 12 March 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Law Day (1 May 1976), signed 25 March 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mother's Day (9 May 1976), signed 6 April 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - National Volunteer Recognition Week (16-22 May 1976), signed 6 April 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Citizenship Day and Constitution Week (17 September 1976), signed 8 September 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Yorktown Day (19 October 1976), signed 23 September 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Veterans Day (11 November 1976), signed 28 September 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Teacher Appreciation Week (1 October 1976), signed 28 September 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Proclamation to Ratify Amendments to the Virginia Constitution, signed 7 December 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American History Month (19 January-22 February 1976), signed 18 December 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 18 (1975) Promulgate and Issue the Commonwealth of Virginia Emergency Operations Plan, Volume III, Operational Survival Plan, War-Caused Disaster (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 19 (1975) Establish the Electricity Cost Commission (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 20 (1975) Amend and Re-Establish the Governor's Manpower Services Council and the Manpower Planning Council (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 21 (1975) Authority and Responsibility of Secretary of Administration and Finance (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 22 (1975) Authority and Responsibility of Secretaries of Commerce and Resources, Education and Human Affairs (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 23 (1975) Assignment of Commissions, Compacts, and Boards to Secretaries (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 24 (1975) Establish the Virginia Energy Resource Advisory Commission (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 25 (1975) State Office on Volunteerism (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 26 (1975) Legislative Coordination and Clearance (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 27 (1975) Remove the Restriction and Disabilities Imposed on George Edward Downing (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arbor Day (14 March 1975), signed 12 February 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Emergency Proclamation, signed 29 May 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hampton-Sydney College Proclaimed a Virginia Bicentennial College, signed 3 September 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Teacher Appreciation Week (1 October 1975), signed 10 September 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Citizenship Day and Constitutional Week (17 September 1975), signed 10 September 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Yorktown Day (19 October 1975), signed 24 September 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Veterans Day (11 November 1975), signed 15 October 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Thanksgiving Day (27 November 1975), signed 17 October 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Emergency Proclamation, signed 22 October 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EO 1 (1974) Affirmative Action Plan for Equal Employment Opportunity (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 2 (1974) Motor Fuels Restricted (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 3 (1974) Maximum Speed Limit for Motor Vehicles (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 4 (1974) Amend/Readopt EO 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 5 (1974) Suspended EO 2 and 4 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 6 (1974) Prescribing Arrangements and Conditions for Development and Coordination of a State Program for Minority Business Enterprise (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 7 (1974) Delegation of Authority, Secretary of Administration (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 8 (1974) Delegation of Authority, Secretary of Commerce and Resources (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 9 (1974) Delegation of Authority, Secretary of Education (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 10 (1974) Delegation of Authority, Secretary of Human Affairs (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 11 (1974) Delegation of Authority, Secretary of Transportation and Public Safety (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 12 (1974) Travel Regulations (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 13 (1974) Establish the Governor's Manpower Services Council and the Governor's Manpower Planning Council (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 14 (1974) Rescission of EO 74 Concerning Donation of Federal Surplus Property (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 15 (1974) Charging the Department of State Police with Responsibility to Establish and Direct a Uniform Accident Prevention and Safety Program (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 16 (1974) State Energy Office (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EO 17 (1974) Amend Conditional Pardon of Charles N. Smith (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Welcome Wagon Ladies recognized (1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Youth Art Month (1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Tall Cedar Week (1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Statler Brothers recognized (1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Navy Virginia Company recognized (1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Palisades High School Madrigal Chorus (1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Recognized Eagle Scout Thomas Edward Bennett (1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Recognized Boy Scouts of America (1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Agriculture Appreciation Week (13 January 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - International Printing Week (14 January 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Martin Luther King, Jr. (15 January 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Heart Fund (1 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Freedom Day (1 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Mental Health Month (1 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Music Month (7 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clergy Week (3 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - African-American History Week (10 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Life Insurance Week in Virginia (10 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American History Month (11 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Edison Science Youth Day (11 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Inventors Week (11 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Vocational Education Week (11 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Brotherhood Week (17 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Engineer's Week (17 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Leukemia Day (17 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Multiple Sclerosis Youth Education Month (22 February 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Kidney Month (1 March 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Peanut Month (1 March 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Nutrition Week (3 March 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Savings and Loan Week (10 March 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Law Day (11 March 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - March of Dimes Telerama (12 March 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ORT Day (14 March 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Institute of Banking Week in Virginia (17 March 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Poison Prevention Week (12 March 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Wildlife Week (17 March 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Doctor's Day (20 March 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Vietnam Veterans Day (29 March 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Action for Foster Children Week (31 March 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Week of the Young Child (31 March 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cancer Control Month (April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve Week (1 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Motor Vehicle Inspection (1 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mother's Day (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Barbershop Harmony Week (7 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Keep Virginia Beautiful Week (8 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Pan American Week (14 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lions White Cane Week (15 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Coin Week (20 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Youth Temperance Education Week (20 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Realtor Week (21 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Secretaries Week (21 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Volunteer Week (21 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - NATO Week (22 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Beta Sigma Phi Week (27 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Championship Canoe Races (27 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cape Henry Day (28 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Child Mental Health Week (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Shenandoah Valle Week (28 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Day of Humiliation, Fasting and Prayer (30 April 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Business Women's Association Recognized (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Family Unity Month (May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - High Blood Pressure Month (May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Parliamentarians' Week (1 May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Senior Citizens Month and Day (May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Good Will Week (5 May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Music Week (5 May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Salute to Nursing Week (5 May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Minerals Week (6 May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Juvenile Diabetes Week (12 May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Nursing Home Week (12 May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Police Week and Peace Officers' Memorial Day (12 May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Transportation Week (12 May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Medical Assistance Week (13 May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Statement on Israeli Massacre of 16 May 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Insurance Women's Week (19 May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Rescue Squad Week (19 May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Maritime Day (22 May 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dairy Month (June 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Special Olympics Day (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Vessel Examination Week (1 June 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National PBX Operators Week (2 June 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Jefferson Davis Day (3 June 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Flag Week (9 June 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Flood Insurance Week (23 June 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Roy Clark Day (23 June 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Safe Boating Week (1 July 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Independence Day (4 July 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - National Baton Twirling Week (14 July 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Captive Nations Week (14 July 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Proclamation re: Potomac River Fisheries Commission (16 July 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Angus Week (21 July 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Citizenship Day and Constitution Week (4 September 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Teacher Appreciation Week (13 September 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - United Way Month (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Veterans Day (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Thanksgiving Day (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Proclamation on the amendment of the Constitution of Virginia (5 December 1974) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Governor Linwood Holton, Jr., 1970-1973 (accession 43291)., Extent: 1 folder. (Box 1)
  - EO 30 (1973) Assistance for Home Heating Fuel Oil (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 31 (1973) Amending Regulations Governing State-Owned Vehicles (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 32 (1973) Order Tax Commissioner to Make Public Anticipated revenue Effect of Exempting Food and Nonprescription Drug Products from Sales and Use Tax (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 33 (1973) Assistance for Home Heating Fuel Oil (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 34 (1973) Provide Charles R. Haugh, Commonwealth's Attorney, Albemarle County with all Confidential Information Available per his Request (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 35 (1973) Establishing a 10 per cent Reduction in State Use of all Sources of Energy (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 36 (1973) Enforced Speed Limit of 55 Miles Per Hour due to Shortage of Motor Vehicle Fuel (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 37 (1973) Direct all Confidential Information Requested by Letter from James A. Cales, Jr., Commonwealth's Attorney, City of Portsmouth (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Emergency Proclamation: Shortage of Kerosene and Heating Oil, signed 23 February 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Law Day (1 May 1973), signed 7 March 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Emergency Proclamation: Tornado Damage, Fairfax County, signed 2 April 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mother's Day (13 May 1973), signed 26 April 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Emergency Proclamation: Shortage of Kerosene and Heating Oil, signed 17 July 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - United Way Month (October 1973), signed 19 September 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Teacher Appreciation Week (1 October 1973), signed 13 September 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yorktown Day (19 October 1973), signed 15 October 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Veteran's Day (11 November 1973), signed 1 November 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Thanksgiving Day (22 November 1973), signed 14 November 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Emergency Proclamation: Reduce Speed Limit to 55 Miles Per Hour, signed 26 November 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Civil Defense Day (7 December 1973), signed 26 November 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 15 (1972) Redistricting of Planning Districts and Multi-Jurisdictional Districts (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 16 (1972) State Department of Purchases and Supply as Official Agency to Acquire, Store and Distribute (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 17 (1972) Virginia Developmental Disabilities Planning and Advisory Council (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 18 (1972) Issue the Virginia Natural Disaster Assistance Relief Plan (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 19 (1972) Revised Travel Regulations (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 20 (1972) Reassign State Executive Agencies (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 21 (1972) Others Given Documentation to Sign Documents (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 22 (1972) Direct the Division of State Planning and Community Affairs to Carry Out Temporary Housing Mission Assigned by Virginia Natural Disaster Assistance Plan necessitated by Storm Agnes (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 23 (1972) Selection of Local Director of Civil Defense (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 24 (1972) Designating Officials to Serve as Representatives on the Project Management Board of the Southeastern Virginia Pendleton Project (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 25 (1972) Order Commissioner of Revenue and Director of Assessments for the City of Alexandria to Disclose all information to correct erroneous real estate errors (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 26 (1972) Direct the Division of State Planning and Community Affairs to Carry Out Temporary Housing Mission Assigned by Virginia Natural Disaster Assistance Plan (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 27 (1972) Establish State Manpower Planning Council (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 28 (1972) Direct Department of Taxation to release sales tax data to the Tennessee Valley Authority (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 29 (1972) Installation of the Virginia Equal Employment Opportunity Plan (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Proclaiming City of Radford a City of the First Class, signed 9 March 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Proclamation to Amend the Constitution of Virginia, signed 29 November 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Emergency Proclamation, Flooding in Southeastern, central and northern Virginia from Hurricane Agnes, signed 23 June 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Emergency Proclamation, Flooding around Hampton, Newport News, Virginia Beach from Weather Phenomenon, signed 28 September 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Emergency Proclamation, Flooding South Central from Weather Phenomenon, signed 9 October 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Law Day (1 May 1972), signed 9 March 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mother's Day (14 May 1972), signed 6 April 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Proclaiming Banks that closed on Friday, June 23, following flooding by Hurricane Agnes were acting under the Governor's Order, signed 8 August 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Teacher Appreciation Week (1 October 1972), signed 26 September 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yorktown Day (19 October 1972), signed 2 October 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Veteran's Day (11 November 1972), signed 6 October 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Thanksgiving Day (23 November 1972), signed 8 November 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 9 (1971) Establish an Office of Special Programs (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 10 (1971) Directing Institute of Marine Science to Conduct a Study of Dawson Shoals Island, Accomack County (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 11 (1971) Order Government Agencies to Comply Fully with President's Cost of Living (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 12 (1971) Regulations Governing Certain State-Owned Vehicles (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 13 (1971) Authorization that Tax and Revenue Officer be Provided with Information (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 14 (1971) Order State of Virginia participate in the Southern Growth Policies Agreement (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Emergency Proclamation: Marshall Street Viaduct to be closed due to Structural Inadequacy, signed 14 April 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Emergency Proclamation: State-wide Ban on Out-Door Burning due to Extraordinary Fire Hazard Conditions, signed 27 April 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Law Day (1 May 1971), signed 19 March 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mother's Day (9 May 1971), signed 16 April 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Veteran's Day (11 November 1971), signed 23 September 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yorktown Day (19 October 1971), signed 29 September 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Teacher Appreciation Week (1 October 1971), signed 1 October 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Marine Corps League Day (10 November 1971), signed 19 March 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Thanksgiving Day (25 November 1971), signed 5 November 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 1 (1970) Establish the Office of Commissioner of Administration (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 2 (1970) Establish the Governor's Management Study (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 3 (1970) Others Given Authorization to Sign Documents (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 4 (1970) Establish the Governor's Council on Narcotics and Drug Abuse Control (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 5 (1970) Amending and Re-Executing the Governor's Council on Narcotics and Drug Abuse Control (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 6 (1970) Amending and Re-Executing the State Law Enforcement Planning Council and the State Law Enforcement Administration (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 7 (1970) Revised Travel Regulations (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EO 8 (1970) Establish the Governor's Council on the Environment (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Proclamation: Amend the Constitution, signed 25 November 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Proclaim: Traffic Safety Program, all Motor Vehicles be Submitted to Inspection, signed 3 July 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Heart Month in Virginia (February 1970), signed 27 January 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Environmental Awareness Week (19 April 1970), signed 17 April 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Law Day (1 May 1970), signed 25 April 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mother's Day (10 May 1970), signed 16 April 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yorktown Day (19 October 1970), signed 29 September 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Veteran's Day (11 November 1970), signed 29 October 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Thanksgiving Day (26 November 1970), signed 10 November 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Governor William M. Tuck, 1948 (accession 43292)., Extent: 1 folder. (Box 1)
  - Executive Order, Establish 1628 as the Historical Date of Organization of the First Virginia Regiment, signed 28 June 1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)